drugbuyers.com 2016-06-16

# Privacy Policy for Drugs.com

Changes were made to this privacy policy on November 9th, 2015. Added clarity on third party service providers and what information we share with these entities. Added link to specific Mobile Application Privacy Policy. Historical changes can be viewed here. 

For the purposes of this privacy policy, the terms "We", "Us", "Our" and "Drugs.com" refer to Our web site www.drugs.com. The terms "You" “Your” and "end-user" refer to You as a user of this web site. This privacy policy applies to www.drugs.com owned and operated by Drugsite Trust, doing business as Drugs.com. This privacy policy describes how Drugsite Trust collects and uses the personal information You provide on Our web site: http://www.drugs.com. It also describes the choices available to You regarding Our use of Your personally identifiable information (PII) and how You can access and update this information and what information may be shared with third party service providers.

## TRUSTe

Drugs.com has received TRUSTe's Privacy Seal signifying that this privacy statement and our practices have been reviewed for compliance with the TRUSTe program viewable on the validation page available by clicking the TRUSTe seal. The TRUSTe program does not cover information that may be collected through downloadable software. The TRUSTe certification only covers information collected on our web site www.drugs.com and does not cover information that may be collected through our Mobile Application(s).

If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact TRUSTe at <https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request>

Click here for Our Mobile Application Privacy Policy.

Contact Details:

> Drugsite Trust  
> 25 Apollo Drive, suite A  
> Auckland 0632  
> New Zealand  
> Telephone: +64 9 476 8500  
> By e-mail: 

Drugs.com does not collect personally identifiable information about You when You visit Our web site unless otherwise stated or unless You choose to provide this information to Us (such as through registration or on information submission forms).

We may collect and store in log files certain information automatically. This information is not shared with anyone beyond Our third party analytics provider and authorized web site support staff, except when required by law enforcement investigation (such as to comply with a judicial proceeding, court order or subpoena), and will be used only as a source of anonymous statistical information. This information may include:

  * Internet Protocol (IP) address of the domain or the proxy provided by Your Internet Service Provider (ISP).
  * Date and time the IP accessed Our site.
  * Pages viewed (recorded by the text and graphics files that compose that page).
  * Web address of the web site.
  * Browser version and operating system.

Drugs.com is the sole owner of the information collected on the Drugs.com web site. We may use aggregate statistics to help Us make Our site more useful to visitors, such as assessing what information is of most and least interest to visitors, and for other purposes such as determining the site’s technical design specifications and identifying system performance or problem areas. We may combine this automatically collected log information with other information We collect about You. We do this to improve services We offer You, to improve marketing, analytics, or site functionality.

This web site contains links to other web sites that are not owned or controlled by Us. Please be aware that We are not responsible for the privacy practices of such other web sites.

We encourage You to be aware when You leave Our web site and to read the privacy policies of each and every web site that collects personally identifiable information.

This privacy statement applies only to information collected by this web site.

### Third Party Service Providers

Drugs.com employs the services of several third party service providers. These partners provide essential services such as relevant content, search results, advertising and analytics. We share some aggregate, non personally identifiable information with these providers in order to improve site functionality, record analytics data and deliver advertising.

### Tracking Technologies

Technologies such as: cookies, beacons, tags and scripts are used by Drugs.com and Our third party service providers.

These technologies are used in analyzing trends, administering the site, tracking users’ movements around the site and to gather demographic information about Our user base as a whole. We may receive reports based on the use of these technologies by these companies on an individual as well as aggregated basis.

We use cookies to remember users’ settings (e.g. language preference) and for authentication. Users can control the use of cookies at the individual browser level. If You reject cookies, You may still use our site, but Your ability to use some features or areas of Our site may be limited.

We use Local Shared Objects, such as Local Storage, such as HTML5, to store content information and preferences. Third parties with whom We partner to provide certain features on Our site or to display advertising based upon Your Web browsing activity use LSOs such as HTML 5 or Flash to collect and store information. Various browsers may offer their own management tools for removing HTML5 LSOs. To manage Flash LSOs please [click here](https://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager07.html).

We partner with third parties to either display advertising on Our Web site or to manage Our advertising on other sites. Our third party partners may use technologies such as cookies to gather information about Your activities on this site and other sites in order to provide You advertising based upon Your browsing activities and interests. If You wish to not have this information used for the purpose of serving You interest-based ads, You may opt-out by [clicking here](https://preferences-mgr.truste.com/). Please note this does not opt You out of being served ads. You will continue to receive generic ads.

## Personally Identifiable Information (PII)

### Form Submission

You may choose to provide Us with personally identifiable information, by sending email with questions or comments or by filling out an online form and submitting it to Us through Our web site. We may use this information to;

  * gather the requested information
  * respond to Your message
  * follow-up as appropriate
  * conduct statistical research

Drugs.com does not create individual profiles with the information You provide. If information is collected, it will be used solely in connection with Drugs.com, or for such other purposes as are described at the point of collection. We will share Your personally identifiable information with third parties only in the ways that are described in this privacy policy.

Drugs.com will not share any personally identifiable information unless specifically agreed to by You, or;

  * when required by law enforcement investigation (such as to comply with a judicial proceeding, court order or subpoena).
  * when We believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to protect Our rights, protect Your safety or the safety of others, investigate fraud, or respond to a government request.
  * in exceptional cases such as in response to threats of physical harm to You or others.
  * to Our third party vendors when required for the provisioning of products and services on behalf of Drugs.com.
  * to conduct research where personally identifiable information will be de-identified, analyzed and compared at an aggregate level for statistical purposes.
  * • if Drugs.com is involved in a merger, acquisition, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, You will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on Our Web site of any change in ownership or uses of Your personally identifiable information, as well as any choices You may have regarding Your personally identifiable information.

However, email and online forms are not secure against interception and senders cannot expect guaranteed privacy.

### Registration

In order to use some areas of this web site, You must first complete the registration form. During registration You are required to provide contact information such as Your name, age, email address, preferred username, password and preferred subscriptions. We will only use this information to contact You about the services on Our web site in which You have expressed interest. You also have the option to provide demographic information to Us; we encourage You to submit this information so We can provide You a more personalized experience on Our web site.

To store any medication list, You will need to create a Drugs.com account. You control who can access or edit Your medication list. Your account will not be accessible to anyone else except for authorized web site support staff or when required by law enforcement investigation (such as to comply with a judicial proceeding, court order or subpoena).

### Community Interaction

If You choose to participate in any community oriented parts of the Drugs.com web site, such as a forum, bulletin board, blog, chatroom, Q&A, reviews or comments section, You should be aware that any personally identifiable information You choose to submit can be read, collected, used by others and may appear in search engines. Such information may also be shared with Our third party service providers. We are not responsible for the personally identifiable information You choose to submit. Drugs.com also reserves the right to terminate the accounts of visitors who use these services in a manner inconsistent with Our Terms of Use.

### Public Profile

The profile You create on Our site will be publically accessible unless otherwise indicated. You may change the privacy settings of Your profile through Your account portal.

### Social Media

Our Web site includes social media features, such as the Facebook like button and widgets, such as a share button or interactive mini-programs that run on Our site. These features may collect Your IP address, which page You are visiting on Our web site, and may set a cookie to enable the feature to function properly. Social media features and widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on Our web site. Your interactions with these features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.

### Opting Out

We provide You the opportunity to ’opt-out’ of having personally identifiable information used for certain purposes, when We ask for this information. For example, if You set up an account but do not wish to receive any additional marketing material from Us, You can indicate Your preference during signup. If You no longer wish to receive Our newsletters, You may opt-out of receiving them by following the instructions included in each newsletter or by signing into Your account or by [emailing us](https://www.drugs.com/support/contact.html).

For advertising opt-out options please click here.

### Removal

To request the removal of publicly displayed personally identifiable information published on the Drugs.com web site, You may contact Us through Our [support system](https://www.drugs.com/support/contact.html). In order for Us to consider Your request, You are required to include links to any page(s) where You believe any such personally identifiable information exists. For each instance, You must also provide clear instructions describing the exact position/location of the personally identifiable information on any page and how it relates to You. 

### Updating and Closing Your Account

If Your personally identifiable information changes, or if You no longer desire Our service, You may update, delete, or deactivate Your information by signing into Your account or by emailing Our [Customer Support](https://www.drugs.com/support/contact.html) or by contacting Us by telephone or via courier at the contact information listed above. We will respond to Your request within a reasonable timeframe.

You may update or close/delete Your account at any time. When a member is signed in, a prominent link is provided to comprehensive account settings including options to permanently delete their account and to opt in or out of email newsletters. Deleting Your account will also remove any personally identifiable information connected with this account.

## Collection and Use of 3rd Party Personally identifiable information

You may also provide personally identifiable information about other people, such as their name and email address. This information is only used for the sole purpose of completing Your request or for whatever reason it may have been provided. This information may be stored in log files. To request removal please contact [Customer Support](https://www.drugs.com/support/contact.html).

## Email Disclosure

If You subscribe to receive email, We will only send messages to notify You about the services on Our site in which You have expressed interest. These emails may contain an occasional sponsor message. Email messages sent to You will always contain at least one clearly visible link to unsubscribe.

## Other Personal Information

You may also provide personal information which is not directly identifiable, such as the phrase entered during a search or when creating a medication list.

### Search

When You search on Drugs.com, We share Your search phrase with third party partners in order to provide relevant search results, advertisements and to provide Us with aggregate analytics which We use to improve site functionality.

### Medication Lists

When You build a medication list on Drugs.com, We do not share any personal information with third party partners except for the purpose of collecting and reporting aggregate drug usage statistics, drug interaction data and drug treatment combinations.

## Security

Drugs.com follows generally accepted industry standards to protect the personally identifiable information submitted to Us, both during transmission and once We receive it. However, no method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure. Therefore, while We strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect all personally identifiable information, We cannot guarantee its absolute security. We use SSL (Secure Socket Layer) technology to protect Your sensitive information (if any) on Our site. If You have any questions about security on Our web site, You can send an [email](https://www.drugs.com/support/contact.html) using Our contact form.

## Data Retention

We will retain Your information for as long as Your account is active or as needed to provide You services. We will retain and use Your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

## URLs

Our web site URLs (web page addresses) may or may not contain words related to content within the web page. We may share URLs You visit with third party service providers in order to provide relevant advertising and to provide Us with aggregate analytics which We use to improve site functionality.

## Changes to the Privacy Policy

If We decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes to this privacy policy and provide notifications on the homepage, and other places we deem appropriate so that You are aware of what information We collect, how We use it, and under what circumstances, if any, We disclose it. We reserve the right to modify this privacy policy at any time, so please review it frequently. If We make material changes to this policy, We will notify You here, or by email, or by means of a notice on Our homepage prior to the change becoming effective.

Updated: November 9th, 2015
